Guide to the University Program in Genetics and Genomics Records, 1963-1993
Duke University. University Archives
University Program in Genetics and Genomics records 1963-1993
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. University Program in Genetics and Genomics.
1.0 linear feet Extent: 1000 Items
The University Program in Genetics and Genomics was founded in 1967 and serves as a primary training environment for students at Duke University interested in graduate Genetics and Genomics. This collection includes memoranda, correspondence, publicity material, printed matter and other records.
RL.01924
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The University Program in Genetics and Genomics Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer starting in 1989.
Historical Note
The Duke University Program in Genetics and Genomics serves as the primary training environment for students at Duke University interested in graduate Genetics and Genomics and has existed for the past 25 years as a forum for those interested in genetic and genomic approaches to questions of biological interest. The program was founded in 1967 and acts as an umbrella graduate training program that spans several basic science and clinical departments and bridges the medical center and the college of arts and sciences.
Collection Overview
This collection includes memoranda, correspondence, publicity material, printed matter and other records.
Detailed Description of Collection
- Container List, 1963-1993, 1.0 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
  The interplay between Arts and Sciences and the Medical School in relation to the development of Genetics at Duke led to the establishment of the Biological Sciences Council.
  - Reports, correspondence and memoranda, 1963-1969 (Box 1)
  - Memoranda and CVs, 1968-1978
  - Memoranda and other material, 1968-1978
  - Printed Matter, 1979-1982
  - Memoranda and flyers, 1979-1982
  - Printed matter and memoranda, 1982
  - Notices of the DU Program in Genetics, 1983-1985
  - Publicity, memoranda, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Printed matter, notices, memoranda, and miscellany, 1987-1993